# ANTON BARANOV

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER - UNITY DEVELOPER

Remote. Krasnoyarsk, Russia

github.com/forcepusher

## SUMMARY

I'm a programmer specializing in real-time multiplayer and WebGL games. I have been involved in commercial game development since 2009 and started using Unity in 2011. I progressed from being an indie developer to becoming a technical director, working across the entire technology stack, including programming, art, analytics, and publishing.

#### **SKILLS**

- Unity Engine
- C#, JavaScript, TypeScript
- · WebGL, Android, iOS, PC
- Git, Jira, Effective Teamwork
- Profiling, Optimization
- Debugging, Crashes/ANRs (Sentry & device logs)
- Multiplayer Networking
- NPC AI (Behavior Trees)
- VContainer, Zenject, etc.
- Company Knowledge Management, Documentation
- Leading small teams (3-5)
- Creating Libraries/SDKs
- R&D, Prototyping
- Gameplay Mechanics Design
- Photoshop, 3dsMax, Spine, Motionbuilder, WorldMachine

#### **EDUCATION**

2006-2012 SIBERIAN FEDERAL **UNIVERSITY** 

• Mathematician, Systems Programmer

## LANGUAGES

- Russian (Native)
- English (B2)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **AGAVA LLC**

2021-2023

Technical Lead -> Technical Director

- Achieved self-sustaining revenue by collaborating closely with Marketing.
- Responsible for the technical stack of a 60-developer company.
- Created a corporate knowledge base consisting of around 80 documents, including step-by-step tutorials for various platforms and problem cases.
- Communicated with foreign partners and negotiated software licensing.
- Opened new production avenues: Mobile WebGL and Playable Ads.
- Led R&D team, developed libraries and SDKs, evaluated new platforms.
- Addressed performance issues in mobile projects when necessary.
- Conducted technical interviews, code reviews, and provided guidance.

#### **Zaprendo Holdings Limited**

2020-2021

Software Engineer

- · Completed a problematic project that changed hands multiple times, overcoming legacy code and a severely outdated engine. This enabled the client to secure ongoing educational grants.
- Fixed bugs, reduced build size, and added cloud save & custom backend
- Assisting with publishing to pass the Apple App Store review process.

#### **Dusk Games**

2018-2020

Software Engineer

- · Rewrote the multiplayer networking for a mobile Battle Royale game, recovering it from a broken state and adding latency compensation.
- Optimized game performance, achieving a boost from 8 FPS to 60 FPS and reducing client network traffic from 40 KB/s to a maximum of 4 KB/s.
- Created bot AI that was barely distinguishable from real players.
- · Programmed core gameplay combat mechanics.

Additional contract work and commercial projects since 2009.

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

- **Dusk Games** Multiplayer mobile Battle Royale game *Frostfall*.
- AGAVA Yandex & Crazy Games broad catalogue of mobile WebGL games.
- AGAVA Yandex Games SDK and other WebGL libraries widely adopted by other companies. Available on GitHub.